http://www.cic.edu/privacy

About CIC
Members of CICMembership InformationMessage from the PresidentMission and HistoryStaff and Senior AdvisorsBoard of DirectorsAnnual ReportsPartners and Sponsors
Programs
All ProgramsFor Campus LeadersLeadership DevelopmentSpecial InitiativesFor Faculty MembersFor State Council MembersFor NetVUE MembersFor Students
Member Services
Tuition Exchange Program (TEP)Visiting Fellows ProgramOnline Course Sharing ConsortiumListservsManage Profile
Resources + Research
Charts and DataResearch Studies and ReportsDigest of Recent ResearchBenchmarking Tools and ServicesAlumni TestimonialsConference PresentationsWebinar Recordings
News + Information
Upcoming EventsIndependent NewsletterCIC in the NewsPress ReleasesEmployment OpportunitiesPresidential Transition
NetVUE staff are also working remotely until further notice. The NetVUE office may still be reached by phone at (616) 395-6750 or by email at lspoelhof@cic.nche.edu. View a list of resources for Thinking about Vocation in a Time of Pandemic.
Privacy Policy
No
Share
Share this page on Twitter
Share this page on Facebook
Share this page on LinkedIn
Print this page
Email this page
Page ContentThe Council of Independent Colleges (CIC) values your privacy and is fully committed to protecting it. This privacy policy outlines CIC’s information collection and dissemination practices. When you are asked to provide information by which you can be identified, you can be assured that those data will be used only in accordance with this privacy statement.CIC may change this policy from time to time in response to new rules and regulations as well as emerging best practices for nonprofit organizations. Therefore, you should check this page on occasion to ensure that you are satisfied with CIC’s information collection and dissemination practices.What information does CIC collect?CIC collects information either directly from you or from other sources such as a representative of your organization, for example during the registration process for a CIC meeting or application process for a CIC program, or a third-party directory. Information acquired from other sources will only be used for a legitimate business interest (that is not overridden by your data protection interests) or through your consent. The type of information CIC collects varies by program/service, but often includes identifying information, such as name, title, address, email address, and phone number.How does CIC use the collected information?CIC collects personal information to provide better service, and in particular, to:Manage accounts and provide transactional information;Provide support for programs and services;Share with members, event participants, and sponsors under specific circumstances and conditions;Promote CIC programs and services; andProvide information about relevant programs and services from CIC partners.CIC will always ask for consent before using information for a purpose other than those stated in this privacy policy.How does CIC use cookies?By using or accessing CIC’s website, you are consenting to CIC’s use of cookies. CIC uses Google Analytics to collect and analyze user activity to improve the website. The collected information, however, will never be combined with personal identifying information. If you wish to opt-out of Google Analytics tracking, you can download the
Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on.How does CIC protect your information?CIC is committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, CIC has put in place suitable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure collected information.Does CIC share collected information?CIC will only disclose or share personally identifiable information with a third party when:Required by law or pursuant to a governmental request;Required to provide requested services;Selection committees review nominations and applications for programs and services;Engaging trusted service providers who assume the responsibilities of data processor to perform services on CIC’s behalf;Requested by a CIC member or sponsor, which may only be used once for a designated and agreed upon purpose; andIn accordance with CIC’s standard liability waiver and release for use of name and photo for a particular CIC program.CIC reserves the right to disclose personal information when it has reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who is violating its terms of use or may be causing injury to or interference with other users or anyone else who could be harmed by such activities.
How long does CIC retain information?When permissible by law, CIC retains collected information indefinitely until advised to delete it. When local law does not permit indefinite retention, for contacts at CIC member institutions, CIC retains collected information for the duration of membership. For contacts at nonmember institutions, collected information is retained up to two years from the date of CIC’s most recent communication.
How can you access your information?You can view and edit your personal information at the
Manage Profile section of the CIC website. You may request a copy of the information CIC has on file about you or request that your personal information be deleted by contacting CIC at
websupport@cic.nche.edu.
How can you contact CIC?If you have any comments or questions about CIC’s Privacy Policy, please contact us at:Council of Independent CollegesOne Dupont Circle, NW, Suite 320Washington, DC 20036 USAEmail:
websupport@cic.nche.eduLast updated: December 18, 2019
Privacy Policy
